Anger Management at Workplace
I'm a 26-year-old woman and
I joined my current workplace 3 years ago.
Despite the tough job market,
I was fortunate to find work right away.
Although I'm young,
I'm building a reputation
for strong performance at work.
I know I can't always get compliments,
and there are bad days at work.
But when my boss tells me
something negative,
I get so angry.
In professional settings,
I need to be able to
hide negative emotions.
But I can't stop crying in anger.
I don't know how I can control my mind.
You should do lots of prostrations.
Do 108 prostrations
first thing in the morning
and repeat this
to yourself:
"No one in this whole world
is exactly the same as me."
Not only the physical appearances,
but also how one sees
and feels about the world
is slightly different for everyone.
Do you understand?
Yet, we tend to see the world
only in our eyes,
and we are all a bit self-centered.
When others are different from us,
we say it's wrong.
We find this frustrating and angry.
Which is why we should lower ourselves
and think, "I have my shortcomings."
"Everyone has their own reasons."
"Everyone has their own reasons
for doing things their way.
I respect that difference."
You need to pray this way.
Although you won't change immediately,
if you continue to remind
yourself of this,
you'll remember that
people have their reasons
when they make you angry.
Long ago, in the midst of being tortured,
I was in a fit of rage,
then I had a sudden insight.
The torturer too is a father
to his children, a husband to his wife,
and a son to his parents
when he goes home.
He'd get praised for being good
at his work
by torturing and getting
confessions out of people.
He'd be considered outstanding
and capable as a torturer.
So when you see things
from his perspective,
he is not some devil incarnate.
He is only trying to do his job well
when he tortures.
When you have experienced
something like this,
you are less bothered by things.
You will still get upset
when someone talks bad about you,
but once you go through
such a profound experience,
you change for the better,
little by little.
Let's say if your anger meter
was at 100 before,
it will go down to 50, and then to 30.
I think my situation
is very different from yours.
My team leader starts the day with frowns
and treats everyone with hostility.
So, I thought
he's probably like that at home too.
But when I went to his house-warming party,
(Audience) Laughter
I saw that although he himself
is a graduate of a top university,
he didn't push his children to study hard.
At home, he wasn't angry at all
and was such a gentle husband
So I thought it would be nice
if he acted at work the way he did at home.
But after listening to you,
I think everyone is like that.
How he acts outside is his true nature.
But he is making an effort
not to be that way with his family.
People think he only treats his family well
and not others.
Meanwhile, his family thinks
he's great outside
but not really with the family.
This is the general perception.
As you see, it depends on
each person's perspective.
For example, if someone makes
an offering at a temple,
would the temple say
it's a good deed or a bad deed?
A good deed
But if the parents
or the family hears this,
what would they say?
They'd call her crazy and complain,
"If you were going to
waste money like that,
you should've just given it to me"
This is how people think.
Because everyone has
a different point of view,
everyone in this world
is different from me.
Their religion, beliefs,
and points of view are all different.
Even a cup like this is seen
from all kinds of different perspectives.
Some may wonder,
"hmm, who made this?"
Some may think, "what is it made of?"
Some may ask, "what is it used for?"
However, those interested in
the person who created it
think everyone should be curious
about the same thing, saying,
"Why use the cup when you don't even know
who the creator is?"
Do you understand?
And those interested in
the material think,
"They don't even know what it's made of,
why do they use the cup?"
"Who cares who created it?
It's the material that is important,"
they might say.
Then what about those
who think function is important?
"Who cares who created it
or what it's made of,
as long as it's useful?" they might say.
People who say "It doesn't matter
who made it as long as it's useful"
Such perspective is
called utilitarianism.
Do you get it?
People who question "who made it?"
are called fundamentalists.
So each person has
a different point of view
when it comes to these things.
People get stuck on
their own way of thinking
and dismiss those who
think differently as bad or weird.
That's why there is
so much conflict in the world.
For instance, among the people
who come to work with a sour face,
some of them may be bringing
to work their marriage problems from home
and that could be the reason
for their bad mood.
But not everyone is the same.
Do you understand?
We think that
"I have no problems at home.
I only get stressed at work
because of him."
But in fact, it could be the case
that you are stressing him out,
and he may be frowning because of you.
The problem is that
when we try to find peace
by changing the other person,
we become dependent on that person.
We are putting ourselves
under his or her thumb.
If I go on smiling in my life,
regardless of whether others are frowning,
I am the master of my life.
If I am happy,
it will make even his life
a little better too.
We want to be on such path of wisdom,
this is why we practice, no?
Unknowingly, you are convinced that
you are always right,
because you are talented and competent.
So when someone is slow at doing things
or makes a mistake,
you can't tolerate it
even if it's your boss.
You think, "he is incompetent,
what a waste of his title."
Because you keep thinking this way,
you become frustrated and angry.
So you need to start learning that
there is no right or wrong
in the first place.
As I suggested before, if you make
the time and go to the training retreat,
the world will become tranquil
to you afterward.
There is no problem in life to begin with.
If you see everything as a problem,
there will be no space in your heart,
and not even a needle
could get through to you.
If you simply let go,
then all problems disappear.
We all live somewhere in the middle,
trying to find the balance
between these two states.
Thank you for your wise words.
(Audience) Applause
There are two cases.
One is you attend the cultivation retreat
and focus on introspection.
Or, you do nothing,
in which case what you heard here
won't mean anything after today.
You need to train continuously
by constantly sending messages
to your inner-self each morning.
Only then, changes can occur.
Despite what we talked today,
when you see his frowns again tomorrow,
it will bother you again.
But if you repeatedly tell yourself
that he has his reasons too,
then in spite of your anger,
you will be more willing to understand:
"Yeah, there must be
some reason for him."
"If I were in his shoes,
I might act the same way."
If you become capable of such thoughts,
your anger and irritation subside.
Is it possible to maintain
this state of mind all the time?
No. Sometimes you can, sometimes not.
But what happens when you keep trying?
When you can maintain it
once, twice, three times and so on,
your limit expands and you become freer.
Conscious shortcomings
arise out of ignorance.
Hence as soon as you hear the Dharma,
you learn and realize right away.
But habits don't work that way.
Habits are hard to fix
and the subconscious forms by habits.
That's why your subconscious mind
does not change easily.
That's why we say it takes time
for your heart to change.
The other day,
we celebrated Buddha's birthday together
with people of other religions.
I performed the ritual of
bathing the statue of Buddha
and a Catholic priest gave the sermon.
On Christmas,
the Catholic priest conducts the mass,
and I give the sermon.
That day, the priest told this story
during the sermon:
One time, he paid a visit
to the late Cardinal Suhwan Kim.
During a group discussion,
the Cardinal called on the priest
and asked,
"What are the two places in the world
that are the farthest from each other?"
The priest thought about
how to answer this question.
He thought,
'is it the end of the universe?
That must be
several light years away..'
As he was thinking about his answer,
the Cardinal said:
"My friend, it's the distance
from the head to the heart."
Do you get it?
There's a big difference between
the changes in your head
and the changes in your heart.
There are changes
we cannot make due to ignorance,
There are also changes
that are difficult to make
because our habits
are hard to change.
It's easy to think,
"Smoking is bad, I should quit."
But actually quitting is not easy
It is only when your heart changes
that your behaviors change.
Do you understand?
Behaviors are directly linked
to our hearts and minds.
You think you act according to your minds,
but you really act
according to your habits.
Everyone likes money, no?
You like it, right?
That's because
we've become accustomed to liking it.
Human beings are not born
to love money from the beginning.
We're born into a society
that loves money,
so we build such habits unknowingly.
But how does the head take this?
We think, "I shouldn't obsess over money,
I shouldn't like money too much."
"It'll ruin my life if I do.
Do our heads know this or not?
We do in our minds.
But when we see money,
we can't help but like it.
Our mind is trained by habit
formed over a long period of time.
it's not something
we can readily control.
So if we want to change our habits,
we need to practice.
We need to make
an effort to change them.
But people want results
without putting any effort in it.
No wonder there's an old saying,
"resolutions last only three days."
Even when you make up your mind,
your decision disappears in three days
and you go right back to your old ways.
Therefore, if we want to
change ourselves,
we need to be first of all
strongly determined,
And we must be persistent
with our efforts.
That’s what we call prayer.
That's what we call practice.
Saying "grant me my wish!"
is not an act of practice.